[
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "In Greek mythology, Medusa was said to be what type of beast?",
    correctAnswer: "Gorgon",
    answers: ["Hydra","Gorgon","Basilisk"]
  },
  {
    id:2,
    question:"What type of EM radiation gives people tans?",
    correctAnswer:"Ultraviolet",
    answers:["Infrared","Gamma","Ultraviolet"]
  },
  {
    id:3,
    question:"The uppermost region of the sun is called the?",
    correctAnswer:"Corona",
    answers:["Photosphere","Chromosphere","Corona"]
  },
  {
    id:4,
    question:"During World War 1, South Africa captured?",
    correctAnswer:"Namibia",
    answers:["Rwanda","Zimbabwe","Namibia"]
  },
  {
    id:5,
    question:"Who is known as the father of Botany?",
    correctAnswer:"Theophrastus",
    answers:["Aristotle","Mendel","Theophrastus"]
  },
  {
    id:6,
    question:"In Greek mythology, who is the twin brother of Artemis?",
    correctAnswer:"Apollo",
    answers:["Ares","Apollo","Hermes"]
  },
  {
    id:7,
    question:"How many black squares are on a chess board?",
    correctAnswer:"32",
    answers:["32","40","48"]
  },
  {
    id:8,
    question:"Which city hosted the first game of the 2006 FIFA World Cup?",
    correctAnswer:"Munich",
    answers:["Berlin","Frankfurt","Munich"]
  },
  {
    id:9,
    question:"Which name refers to the brightness of a star?",
    correctAnswer:"Magnitude",
    answers:["Magnitude","Albedo","Density"]
  },
  {
    id:10,
    question:"Which river separates China and North Korea?",
    correctAnswer:"Yalu",
    answers:["Laoha","Xiliao","Yalu"]
  },
  {
    id:11,
    question:"Another name for sodium chloride?",
    correctAnswer:"Salt",
    answers:["Flour","Sugar","Salt"]
  },
  {
    id:12,
    question:"In greek mythology, which god fathered nine daughters known as the ‘Muses’?",
    correctAnswer:"Zeus",
    answers:["Zeus","Poseidon","Hades"]
  },
  {
    id:13,
    question:"‘Jack the Ripper’ is credited with how many murders?",
    correctAnswer:"5",
    answers:["5","8","11"]
  },
  {
    id:14,
    question:"Which county invented origami?",
    correctAnswer:"Japan",
    answers:["Japan","China","Russia"]
  },
  {
    id:15,
    question:"Which bone is found in the wrist?",
    correctAnswer:"Capitate",
    answers:["Cochlea","Cramium","Capitate"]
  },
  {
    id:16,
    question:"Who was the first member to leave the pop group ’The Spice Girls’?",
    correctAnswer:"Geri",
    answers:["Emma","Geri","Mel C"]
  },
  {
    id:17,
    question:"Albert Einstein was born in which country?",
    correctAnswer:"Germany",
    answers:["Poland","Germany","Switzerland"]
  },
  {
    id:18,
    question:"The 2004 Olympic Games were hosted in which country?",
    correctAnswer:"Greece",
    answers:["Greece","Australia","Atlanta"]
  },
  {
    id:19,
    question:"What is the sum of the dots on opposite faces of a standard dice?",
    correctAnswer:"7",
    answers:["7","9","10"]
  },
  {
    id:20,
    question:"A traditional gift for a 30th wedding anniversary is?",
    correctAnswer:"Pearl",
    answers:["Ivory","Pearl","China"]
  },
  {
    id:21,
    question:"Triton is a moon of which planet?",
    correctAnswer:"Neptune",
    answers:["Uranus","Neptune","Saturn"]
  },
  {
    id:22,
    question:"Bronze is an alloy of copper and which other metal?",
    correctAnswer:"Tin",
    answers:["Lead","Iron","Tin"]
  },
  {
    id:23,
    question:"In a game of Texas Hold-em Poker, which of the following is the highest hand?",
    correctAnswer:"Flush",
    answers:["Full House","Straight","Flush"]
  },
  {
    id:24,
    question:"The planet Jupiter is named for which Greek god?",
    correctAnswer:"Zeus",
    answers:["Zeus","Hercules","Apollo"]
  },
  {
    id:25,
    question:"In 1912, the famous ocean liner Titanic sank in which ocean?",
    correctAnswer:"North Atlantic",
    answers:["North Atlantic","South Atlantic","Arctic"]
  },
  {
    id:26,
    question:"In Roman numerals, which letter signifies 100?",
    correctAnswer:"C",
    answers:["M","D","C"]
  },
  {
    id:27,
    question:"A brogue is a type of?",
    correctAnswer:"Shoe",
    answers:["Hat","Shoe","Guitar"]
  },
  {
    id:28,
    question:"What is the longest running American animated TV show?",
    correctAnswer:"The Simpsons",
    answers:["The Simpsons","Pokemon","Rugrats"]
  },
  {
    id:29,
    question:"What constellation can be found on the Australian flag?",
    correctAnswer:"Southern Cross",
    answers:["Southern Cross","Big Dipper","Scorpius"]
  },
  {
    id:30,
    question:"In the NATO phonetic alphabet, the letter H stands for which word?",
    correctAnswer:"Hotel",
    answers:["Hammer","Hotel","Hello"]
  },
  {
    id:31,
    question:"Iceberg is a type of…?",
    correctAnswer:"Lettuce",
    answers:["Cabbage","Cauliflower","Lettuce"]
  },
  {
    id:32,
    question:"Ronald Reagan served as US president during which decade?",
    correctAnswer:"1980s",
    answers:["1960s","1970s","1980s"]
  },
  {
    id:33,
    question:"Which of the following is a bird AND a fruit?",
    correctAnswer:"Kiwi",
    answers:["Kiwi","Juju","Mango"]
  },
  {
    id:34,
    question:"Since 1917, what has the Pulitzer Prize been awarded for?",
    correctAnswer:"Journalism",
    answers:["Journalism","Cooking","Research"]
  },
  {
    id:35,
    question:"What was Pinocchio made of?",
    correctAnswer:"Wood",
    answers:["Straw","Wood","Porcelain"]
  },
  {
    id:36,
    question:"Which is the sixth planet from the sunset?",
    correctAnswer:"Saturn",
    answers:["Saturn","Neptune","Jupiter"]
  },
  {
    id:37,
    question:"Which plant is the source of linen?",
    correctAnswer:"Flax",
    answers:["Rattan","Hemp","Flax"]
  },
  {
    id:38,
    question:"Which of the following is an Asian art form involving plants?",
    correctAnswer:"Bonsai",
    answers:["Bonsai","Wasabi","Sudoku"]
  },
  {
    id:39,
    question:"How many arms does a squid have?",
    correctAnswer:"8",
    answers:["8","12","16"]
  },
  {
    id:40,
    question:"According to the bible, on which mountain did Noah’’s Ark run aground?",
    correctAnswer:"Mount Ararat",
    answers:["Mount Nebo","Mount Ararat","Mount Sinai"]
  },
  {
    id:41,
    question:"Dan Brown’s book ‘The Da Vinci Code’ was banned in which country?",
    correctAnswer:"Lebanon",
    answers:["Italy","Lebanon","Vatican City State"]
  },
  {
    id:42,
    question:"Chicago is located on the shore of which state?",
    correctAnswer:"Lake Michigan",
    answers:["Lake Erie","Lake Michigan","Lake Superior"]
  },
  {
    id:43,
    question:"The binary system uses which 2 digits?",
    correctAnswer:"1 and 0",
    answers:["1 and 0","10 and 100","1 and 2"]
  },
  {
    id:44,
    question:"Which term is used to describe a rising stock market?",
    correctAnswer:"Bull",
    answers:["Tiger","Bear","Bull"]
  },
  {
    id:45,
    question:"Which celestial body does not directly orbit the sun?",
    correctAnswer:"The moon",
    answers:["Jupiter","Pluto","The moon"]
  },
  {
    id:46,
    question:"On stage, Michael Jackson famously wore only one?",
    correctAnswer:"Glove",
    answers:["Show","Sock","Glove"]
  },
  {
    id:47,
    question:"Which particle does NOT carry an electric charge?",
    correctAnswer:"Neutrino",
    answers:["Electron","Neutrino","Proton"]
  },
  {
    id:48,
    question:"Gatwick airport can be found near which European capital?",
    correctAnswer:"London",
    answers:["Paris","London","Madrid"]
  },
  {
    id:49,
    question:"What was the given name of the US President known as JFK?",
    correctAnswer:"John",
    answers:["John","Joe","Jerry"]
  },
  {
    id:50,
    question:"Which chess piece moves in an L shape?",
    correctAnswer:"Knight",
    answers:["Queen","Knight","Bishop"]
  },
  {
    id:51,
    question:"What sport is played at Wimbledon, England?",
    correctAnswer:"Tennis",
    answers:["Cricket","Tennis","Football"]
  },
  {
    id:52,
    question:"Spider-Man lives in which city?",
    correctAnswer:"New York",
    answers:["New York","Metropolis","Gotham City"]
  },
  {
    id:53,
    question:"Who wrote the science fiction novel, ‘A Journey to the Centre of the Earth’?",
    correctAnswer:"Jules Verne",
    answers:["Mark Twain","Jules Verne","Isaac Asimov"]
  },
  {
    id:54,
    question:"What device is used to measure tempo?",
    correctAnswer:"Metronome",
    answers:["Metronome","Tuning Fork","Spectrometer"]
  },
  {
    id:55,
    question:"On average, a koala spends 20 hours a day…?",
    correctAnswer:"Sleeping",
    answers:["Sleeping","Eating","Climbing"]
  },
  {
    id:56,
    question:"Which leaf is found on the Canadian flag?",
    correctAnswer:"Maple",
    answers:["Oak","Beech","Maple"]
  },
  {
    id:57,
    question:"Phnom Penh is the capital of which country?",
    correctAnswer:"Cambodia",
    answers:["Laos","Malaysia","Cambodia"]
  },
  {
    id:58,
    question:"The human body is primarily made of?",
    correctAnswer:"Water",
    answers:["Fat","Protein","Water"]
  },
  {
    id:59,
    question:"Al Capone was a famous American what?",
    correctAnswer:"Gangster",
    answers:["Gangster","Author","Politician"]
  },
  {
    id:60,
    question:"Which is NOT a state of matter?",
    correctAnswer:"Frozen",
    answers:["Solid","Frozen","Gas"]
  },
  {
    id:61,
    question:"A painting made with water colors is called a what?",
    correctAnswer:"Aquarelle",
    answers:["Mosaic","Aquarelle","Graffiti"]
  },
  {
    id:62,
    question:"Who wrote ‘The Adventures of Tom Sawyer’?",
    correctAnswer:"Mark Twain",
    answers:["Mark Twain","Huckleberry Finn","Oscar Wilde"]
  },
  {
    id:63,
    question:"Which credit card usually features a centurion on its face?",
    correctAnswer:"American Express",
    answers:["American Express","Visa","MasterCard"]
  },
  {
    id:64,
    question:"Mark Zuckerberg founded which company?",
    correctAnswer:"Facebook",
    answers:["Wikipedia","Google","Facebook"]
  },
  {
    id:65,
    question:"Which type of bird is often associated with wisdom?",
    correctAnswer:"Owl",
    answers:["Sparrow","Stork","Owl"]
  },
  {
    id:66,
    question:"A dehumidifier removes what from the air?",
    correctAnswer:"Water",
    answers:["Smell","Water","Smoke"]
  },
  {
    id:67,
    question:"Which vegetable takes its name from a European city?",
    correctAnswer:"Brussels sprouts",
    answers:["Brussels sprouts","Dublin potatoes","Manchester berries"]
  },
  {
    id:68,
    question:"What is the outer layer of the trunk of a tree called?",
    correctAnswer:"Bark",
    answers:["Pith","Sapwood","Bark"]
  },
  {
    id:69,
    question:"The SETI project involves the search for…?",
    correctAnswer:"Aliens",
    answers:["Aliens","Elves","Ghosts"]
  },
  {
    id:70,
    question:"What is the largest continent by area?",
    correctAnswer:"Asia",
    answers:["Europe","Africa","Asia"]
  },
  {
    id:71,
    question:"Marsupials have what unique feature?",
    correctAnswer:"Pouches",
    answers:["Webbed feet","Night vision","Pouches"]
  },
  {
    id:72,
    question:"The seasonal movement of animals over long distances is called?",
    correctAnswer:"Migration",
    answers:["Migration","Translation","Vacation"]
  },
  {
    id:73,
    question:"When was smallpox declared to be eradicated from the world?",
    correctAnswer:"1980",
    answers:["1940","1980","2000"]
  },
  {
    id:74,
    question:"Which organ is part of the digestive system?",
    correctAnswer:"Stomach",
    answers:["Stomach","Kidneys","Lungs"]
  },
  {
    id:75,
    question:"Brass is an alloy of Zinc and which other material?",
    correctAnswer:"Copper",
    answers:["Lead","Copper","Gold"]
  },
  {
    id:76,
    question:"What is radar used for?",
    correctAnswer:"Detecting objects",
    answers:["Measuring flux","Amplifying sound","Detecting objects"]
  },
  {
    id:77,
    question:"Yellow and blue combine to create?",
    correctAnswer:"Green",
    answers:["Blue","Green","Orange"]
  },
  {
    id:78,
    question:"Which is the lightest metal?",
    correctAnswer:"Aluminum",
    answers:["Aluminum","Lead","Iron"]
  },
  {
    id:79,
    question:"Who was the Greek God of victory?",
    correctAnswer:"Nike",
    answers:["Nike","Hebe","Victorious"]
  },
  {
    id:80,
    question:"Complete the saying: ‘All the world’s a…’’?",
    correctAnswer:"Stage",
    answers:["Oyster","Stage","Home"]
  },
  {
    id:81,
    question:"Which country is NOT a part of Scandinavia?",
    correctAnswer:"Italy",
    answers:["Norway","Sweden","Italy"]
  },
  {
    id:82,
    question:"How many years in a millennium?",
    correctAnswer:"1,000",
    answers:["1,000","10,000","100"]
  },
  {
    id:83,
    question:"Which country is part of South America?",
    correctAnswer:"Argentina",
    answers:["Argentina","Ghana","Mexico"]
  },
  {
    id:84,
    question:"What is the largest living animal?",
    correctAnswer:"Blue Whale",
    answers:["African Elephant","Blue Whale","Giant Squid"]
  },
  {
    id:85,
    question:"How many hydrogen atoms in a water molecule?",
    correctAnswer:"2",
    answers:["4","2","1"]
  },
  {
    id:86,
    question:"Where did the 2016 Summer Olympics take place?",
    correctAnswer:"Rio de Janeiro",
    answers:["Athens","Rio de Janeiro","Jakarta"]
  },
  {
    id:87,
    question:"What is an archipelago?",
    correctAnswer:"Island group",
    answers:["River delta","Island group","Headland"]
  },
  {
    id:88,
    question:"What is grown in a paddy field?",
    correctAnswer:"Rice",
    answers:["Rice","Wheat","Corn"]
  },
  {
    id:89,
    question:"The chemical element Mercury is also known as?",
    correctAnswer:"Quicksilver",
    answers:["Quicksilver","Fermium","Gallium"]
  },
  {
    id:90,
    question:"What is the official national sport of Cuba?",
    correctAnswer:"Baseball",
    answers:["Volleyball","Boxing","Baseball"]
  },
  {
    id:91,
    question:"Where is Tunisia located?",
    correctAnswer:"Africa",
    answers:["Africa","Europe","South America"]
  },
  {
    id:92,
    question:"What was banned in the USA during the Prohibition?",
    correctAnswer:"Alcohol",
    answers:["Gambling","Smoking","Alcohol"]
  },
  {
    id:93,
    question:"Aurora is the Roman Goddess of what?",
    correctAnswer:"Dawn",
    answers:["Fertility","Thunder","Dawn"]
  },
  {
    id:94,
    question:"What topping is needed for a pizza funghi?",
    correctAnswer:"Mushrooms",
    answers:["Artichokes","Mushrooms","Anchovy"]
  },
  {
    id:95,
    question:"What is the name of cards used for fortune telling?",
    correctAnswer:"Tarot",
    answers:["Poker","Tarot","Solitaire"]
  },
  {
    id:96,
    question:"Which is the largest US state by area?",
    correctAnswer:"Alaska",
    answers:["Hawaii","Texas","Alaska"]
  },
  {
    id:97,
    question:"What fruit grows in bunches and is known as ‘hands’?",
    correctAnswer:"Banana",
    answers:["Pear","Banana","Kiwi"]
  },
  {
    id:98,
    question:"Which unit is measured in watts?",
    correctAnswer:"Power",
    answers:["Density","Power","Volume"]
  },
  {
    id:99,
    question:"Salvador Dali belonged to which artistic school?",
    correctAnswer:"Surrealism",
    answers:["Mannerism","Surrealism","Baroque"]
  },
  {
    id:100,
    question:"10 x 10 x 10 = ?",
    correctAnswer:"1000",
    answers:["10,000","1000","300"]
  },
  {
    id:101,
    question:"What is 60 divided by 5?",
    correctAnswer:"12",
    answers:["15","12","10"]
  },
  {
    id:102,
    question:"What is 1004 divided by 2?",
    correctAnswer:"502",
    answers:["52","502","520"]
  },
  {
    id:103,
    question:"19 + ……. = 42?",
    correctAnswer:"23",
    answers:["23","61","32"]
  },
  {
    id:104,
    question:"190 - 87 + 16?",
    correctAnswer:"119",
    answers:["261","87","119"]
  },
  {
    id:105,
    question:"What is 1000 x 1?",
    correctAnswer:"1000",
    answers:["1","1000","0"]
  }
]